ANIL ENES CALIS

Platform Engineer/Site Reliability Engineer

Address Istanbul, Turkey 34862

Phone +90 (530) 350 2652

E-mail anilenescalis@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://linkedin.com/in/anilenescalis/

WWW https://anilenescalis.github.io/

WWW https://github.com/anilenescalis

As an IT Platform engineer and SRE engineer with +2 year experience, I have background in managing and continually optimizing container technologies, cloud platforms and on-premise systems. I have been effective in integrating new technologies and open-source software by prioritizing the security of the systems. In addition, I am a strong person in close cooperation with other engineers, active listening, systematic communication and leadership skills.

Work History

2022-09 - Current

IT Application Systems Specialist

LC Waikiki, Bagcilar/Istanbul

- E-Commerce/Core Business Kubernetes Infrastructure/Platform Management (OpenShift, Rancher, GKE, AKS Vanilla, Lens)
- E-Commerce/Core Business Middleware Application Management (Harbor, Calico, Ingress, Istio, Hashicorp Consul, Vault, Opentelemetry, Jaeger etc.)
- E-Commerce Search Service, Cache DB, Queue Application Management (Elasticsearch, OpenSearch, Redis, Rabbit)
- Chaos Engineering Platform and Reliability Management (Gremlin, StormForge)
- Bash, Ansible, Terraform, Packer, PowerShell Scripting Experience (AWX Tower Management)
- Microsoft Configuration Manager Tools (SCCM Management)
- Core Business CI/CD Pipeline Management (AzureDevops, ArgoCD, Jenkins)
- Opensource Database Installations Experience (MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MariaDB)
- Troubleshooting and Management Tools (ELK Stack, OpenSearch, Grafana, Prometheus, AlertManager, Zabbix, Jaeger)

2021-08 - 2022-09

IT Application Systems Assistant Specialist

LC Waikiki, Bagcilar/Istanbul

- Server Management, Server Installation, Virtualization, Backup Management (VMware, Proxmox Experience, Hyper-V, Oracle VirtualBox)
- Internet Information Services Management Support (IIS Manage Domains)
- Application and Infrastructure Monitoring (Zabbix, Grafana, Prometheus, AppDynamics, Solardwinds, Instana)
- Cloud Infrastructure Management (Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud)

- Linux Web Server (Apache, Tomcat, Nginx)
- F5 Use Experience (Load Balancing of application server farm)

Education

2014-09 - 2020-10 Bachelor of Science: Electrical And Electronics Engineering

Eskisehir Osmangazi University - Eskisehir

 Awarded Window Cleaning Robot Design and Implementation (TUBITAK 2209-B Industry Focused Undergraduate Graduation Thesis)

Skills

Kubernetes Management

Linux Management

DevOps CI/CD

Middleware Environment Management

Infrastructure as Code (IaC)



Excellent

Excellent

Certifications

2023-03 Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (Validation Number: 1629-5963)

2022-08 Gremlin hereby certifies (56312987)

2023-03 Google Cloud OnBoard: Core Infrastructure

Languages

English (B2)
Germany (A2)
Turkish (Native)

Hobbies

- Tennis
- Football
- Sailing
- Rowing Sport